ICE attempted to kidnap Mother in broad daylight without a warrant.
You know Spanish?
You speak Spanish?
She doesn't speak?
No, she does not speak English.
Okay, well, we need to bring her in here and talk to her and we will get our interpreter
on the phone so that everything is clear.
We can interpret right now.
No, we can't have you interpret.
The situation quickly escalated.
Do you want her to talk to the interpreter or do you want us to just take her?
I want you to follow the goddamn law.
This is absurd.
How do you sleep at night?
Do you think that we would be out here doing this if we weren't within?
Yes, I do.
You would not.
Yes, you do.
Oh, shut up.
This is absurd.
She has children.
How many children?
Two daughters.
How old are they?
A year and six months.
Where are they?
They are at home.
With whom?
With their grandmother.
They kept insisting on taking her without giving any explanation.
If you show me a warrant that says you have a right to take us back there, then yes, I will go.
An officer eventually agreed and called a translator using her own phone.
Can you please ask her current address?
They also questioned her about children and what her friends had already told them.
In the end, they let them go, but the emotional impact of what happened won't be going away anytime soon.